only 12 hours a day, people would want
to know, "You feeling okay? Like what's
what's the problem, right?" So, I would
get in around 7:00 in the morning
thinking, "I'm going to work until 8:00
or 9:00 anyway." So, I get in at 7:00 in
the morning. We had something called the
trunk line.
Where the unclassified phones in the
office
were connected to a Washington exchange.
So, even though I'm in Pakistan, I've
got a 202 number. And I I can dial a 202
number like a local call. So, I would
get in before everybody else and I would
always call my then girlfriend, my
post-divorce girlfriend, who became my
second wife. She was a senior CIA
officer.
So, um
I would always end our conversations by
saying, "Okay, love you. Mwah." and hang
up.
And one of the old-timers, there were
seven old men who worked for me.
They were all like very senior senior
intelligence service level officers. All
of them had been at least
director of Near Eastern operations. One
of them had been the deputy director of
the CIA. And they all volunteered to
come back as contractors after 9/11 just
for patriotic reasons. But, if you're a
contractor, you can't have a management
position. So, they worked for me, which
is That must have been interesting. I
learned more from those guys
in 6 months than I learned in the rest
of the entirety of my career.
But, anyway, one of them heard me
finish the call and hang up.
And he says,
"So, are there wedding bells in the
future?" And I said, "Oh, I don't know.
I just got divorced and I'm kind of
afraid of being a two-time loser."
And he says, "Two-time loser?
Jim, how many times have you been
married?" He says, "Four for me."
"Dave, how many times have you been
married?" "I got five."
"Bill, how many times you been married?"
"Three." And he says, "And I got four."
"Don't worry about being a two-time
loser. It comes with the job." Well, the
truth is that the CIA has the highest
divorce rate in all of government
because
you are trained to lie and you lie all
day
everyday. And a lot of guys can't turn
it off when they go home at night. And
And so, I was watching another
conversation you were having. If you
don't mind me asking, how did that end?
How did the first marriage end? Um
in April of 2000.
We were living in Athens.
Tough tough assignment for me because we
were critical threat for for terrorism.
Athens, Greece to be clear. Not cuz
there is an Athens, Ohio. Athens, Ohio.
>> that's where your boy Joey Burrow's
from.
>> Yeah. Okay. That's right. Yeah. Yeah.
So, um
I'm shaving, getting ready for work. And
my oldest son was 6 years old at the
time. He's sitting on the floor next to
me watching me shave. And I'm asking
him, "So, what are you going to do
today? What are you going to learn
today?
You know, what what are you going to
play at the at recess?" And then he says
to me,
"I told Mommy she shouldn't kiss Uncle
Stelios on the lips. She should only
kiss you on the lips. And she told me to
mind my own business."
I felt like I had been electrocuted.
So, I wiped the shaving cream off my
face. I went into the bedroom. She was
sleeping and I kicked the bed.
And she says, "What?"
I said, "Who the is Stelios?"
She said, "Where did you hear that
name?" I said, "Who is he?"
And then she said, "Don't believe
everything a 6-year-old says."
And I said, "I'm going to leave
before I do something that I'm going to
regret for the rest of my life."
And so, I got in the car and I went to
work.
And um
that afternoon, she started calling me.
Like calling me every 5 seconds.
And I just would let it go to voicemail.
Finally, the secretary came into my
office and she said, um
"John, your wife's on the phone and
she's crying." I said, "Yeah, she she
should be crying."
And she said, "No, no, she was in a car
accident and she's injured."
And I was like, "For God's sake." So, I
She was calling my phone again. So, I
picked it up and I said, "What?"
And she said, "I had gotten an accident
and I'm injured and the kids are crying
and
so, I drove up to the accident scene.
And
the car was She was first in in a
left-hand turn lane to make a left.
There was a guy five cars back. Greeks
are very impatient drivers. She went to
make the left. He came from the back and
just T-boned her
and pushed the car up onto the sidewalk
and demolished it and she broke her
wrist and it was a big mess.
So, I go up there
and uh
get out of my car, my fully armored, you
know, BMW 540 with, you know, my two
guns.
And uh
and I said to him, "Ti stathike allo
egine etho? What what what happened
here?"
And he gets all excited. He says, "Eiden
enan ekso, your wife in a putana. She's
a whore."
I said, "My wife is a whore?"
And then
he was in a coma for quite a while.
3 days. Oh, you had that that built up.
All Any other day, I would have let it
go.
>> Yeah. Any other day. So, I got arrested.
Right. Oh, you did? Oh, yeah. And I
>> How do you arrest a CIA station chief?
>> No, no, I wasn't the chief. Um I I uh
I said, "Look, I have diplomatic
immunity."
So, you know, I'm sorry. I'm wrong. I
admit I'm wrong, but I have diplomatic
immunity. And they're like, "Okay, just
sit in the cell." They left the cell
door open and they let me keep my gun,
which was nuts.
But then, um
they brought me in
and um
the guy He was clearly concussed.
He hadn't yet kind of, you know,
faded out.
That was at the hospital later. But, uh
he was sitting there in a chair and he's
just like You could see like the
the birds tweeting, you know, the from
the cartoons.
And uh
he says to me, "So, what happened?"
So, I told the story.
And then this is the police captain for
the whole station.
And he says to the to the guy,
"Is that true? You called his wife a
whore?" And he said,
"I Yes, we got in an accident. She She
yelled at me. I called her a
I did not know that it is a crime to
call a man's wife a in Greece."
And so, they charged him.
And I said, "Listen,
I'm
I can't get charged cuz I have
diplomatic immunity. But, but in good
conscience,
you know, please don't charge him.
I I beat him like almost to death."
Um so, they ended up dropping the
charge.
He filed a lawsuit against me later, but
because I had immunity, it was just
thrown out. And [clears throat]
the only fight I've ever been in in my
entire life. And she said, "I want a
divorce. I'm not living like this
anymore."
And so, the plane landed in New York. I
caught a connection to Washington. She
caught a connection to Cleveland.
And that was the end of it.
Was that the end of it for Stelios, too?
Yeah.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Yeah, I uh They didn't wind up together.
>> No, no. The guy could barely read.
That was uh no. [laughter]
She was feeling lonely and it was
because I was so focused on the job.
It was very hard to maintain a marriage
in the CIA.
>> Very much so. Very very much so. Are you
a good liar?
I think I am a good liar. Yeah.
Why?
Why am I a good liar?
Because deep down, I believe we're the
good guys.
And lying in
service of my country was something that
I I became good at.
I remember my [music] first operational
boss telling me,
"As a general rule," he said, "never lie
to medical, finance, or security.
They'll put you in prison.
Never lie to me.
I'll put you in the hospital."
So, assume that I'm I'm one of your sons
or assume that I'm a close brother of
yours and we haven't seen each other for
20 years and you're prepping me for the
rest of my life. This may be the only
conversation we're going to get to have.
So, whatever truths you have, you're not
going to get to tell me 10 years from
now, 20 years from now. Like give me
give me the stuff now. What do you tell
me?
>> tell you that
again, this is going to sound cynical,
so I apologize in advance.
Tell you that
it's been my experience that the world
is usually not what it seems.
Right? You can never get inside the head
of another human being. You just can't.
We may think we really truly know
somebody. We don't. We never know what's
going on. We never know what's going on
in people's private lives.
Um and so, you always have to be wary
and you have to be self-protective.
The CIA actively seeks to hire people
who have sociopathic tendencies.
People not sociopaths.
Sociopaths have no conscience.
People with sociopathic tendencies do
have a conscience.
They do react in a polygraph exam. But,
because we believe we're the good guys,
we're happy to work in legal, moral, and
ethical gray areas.
But,
sociopaths
easily slip through the the process
because you can't trip them up on a
polygraph.
They have no conscience.
So, they don't react.
That's the problem.
Sociopaths slip through. Now, you know
as well as anybody that
that sociopaths are common among um
C-suite officials in companies. That's
how they got to be CEOs, CFOs, COOs.